cuyahogacounty.us 2013-09-22

# Privacy Policy and Security Statement - Cuyahoga County of Ohio

You are here: Privacy Policy and Security Statement

**Public Records**

Subject to certain statutory exceptions, most documents and records maintained by the Cuyahoga County Information Services Center, including electronic data, are public records under Ohio law. Therefore, information submitted through this Web site may be subject to disclosure pursuant to a public records request.

**Online Forms and E-mail**

This Web site will not collect personally identifiable information (such as name, address, telephone number, etc.) unless you provide such information voluntarily. We may ask for such information in order to respond to your inquiries, add you to subscriber or program lists and other purposes. You are free to provide or not to provide the requested information, but failure to provide may impede our ability to serve you. Any personal information you provide voluntarily, including information submitted through online forms and e-mail, will be used for the purposes stated on the Web page. All E-mail addresses maintained by Cuyahoga County contain the names of people who voluntarily communicated with or requested information from us. Currently, E-mail addresses or any personally identifying information about individuals are not sold or rented to any governmental or commercial entities. When a user has given us his/her E-mail address for purposes of communicating with or requesting information from Cuyahoga County, that communications may become a part of the public record and may be subject to disclosure under applicable Ohio and Federal statute(s).

**Cookies and Scripts**

A data file linking your computer to this web site (commonly referred to as a "cookie") may be created, depending on the settings of your web browser. Temporary cookies may be used when necessary to complete a transaction, to process data submitted to us online or to remember preferred settings (such as text size). Similarly, this Web site may use different types of scripts to provide certain functionality. Data collected by cookies and scripts may be subject to disclosure pursuant to a public records request, but typically do not include personally identifying information. You may disable cookies and scripts in your Web browser's settings, but doing so may disable some features of this site.

**Usage Statistics**

In order to generate usage statistics to help us improve our web site, we automatically collect certain information on every visitor to the web site. However, this information does not disclose "personal identifiers" (such as name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, etc.). Each time a request is made to view a page within this web site, our web site creates a log file capturing generic user information. Examples of this type of information includes the type of Internet browser or computer operating system you are using, the date and time you accessed this site, the Internet protocol address of the individual computer (or proxy server) making the request, and the Internet address of the site from which you may have linked to this site. All information collected by way of server log files is used in aggregate form only and may be analyzed for trends and statistics.

**Security Measures**

The Cuyahoga County Information Services Center takes very seriously the integrity of the information and systems that we maintain. Therefore, we have instituted security measures for all information systems under our control. For security purposes and to ensure that this service remains available to all users, our Web site also employs measures to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. Maintenance of this Web site does not constitute authorization to access any other data maintained by Cuyahoga County, nor does it constitute authorization to access any other portions of the Cuyahoga County network system. Attempts to access any portion of the County network beyond will be subject to prosecution, and such other sanctions as are permitted by law. Unauthorized attempts to upload information or change information on this service are strictly prohibited and may be punishable under applicable Ohio and Federal statute(s).
